

# **Gustavo Rayos**



575-520-5199



gustavorayos @outlook.com



San Francisco Bay Area



gustavorayos.com



@gustavorayos



@qustavorayos

# Summary

Dedicated Computer Systems Engineer with 5 years' experience in System Administration, Security, Networks, and Development and has an active DoD Secret Security Clearance. Performs system configuration, workstation patching, vulnerability management, and network analysis. Leads software, security, group policy, and vulnerability management initiatives from a technical aspect. Has developed in PowerShell, Bash, Java, CSS, and JavaScript. Received Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science from New Mexico State University.

#### Skills

#### LANGUAGES

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

- PowerShell SCCM Bash WDS & MDT DOS/Windows SCAP Java STIGViewer JavaScript Active Directory CSS Group Policy • HTML • Linux (RHEL)
  - Tenable • DHCP • DNS Mac OS
    - Git

VMWare

• Hyper-V

# Work Experience

# INFORMATION SYSTEMS ANALYST (DOD SECRET SECURITY CLEARANCE) Lockheed Martin Space | Sunnyvale, CA | November 2020 - Current

- Performed successful root cause analysis for problem resolution in Windows environments.
- Analyzed and assessed server performance, storage capacity and planning for future needs.
- Performed routine server/workstation patching per guidelines.
- Performed Cyber-security tasks such as apply system SCANs, STIGs, Controls, Policies, perform remediation develop POAMs, and support security audits.
- Successfully installed server and associated hardware.
- Successfully installed/configured software applications and programs.
- Created/edited Standard Operating Instructions (SOI) documentation.
- DoD Secret Security Clearance.

#### SYSTEMS ENGINEER (DOD SECRET SECURITY CLEARANCE)

#### Raytheon Missile Systems | Tucson, AZ | March 2019 - October 2020

- Developed software package which automates our standard operating system (OS) configuration on Test Equipment (TE).
- Deployed a Windows Deployment Server (WDS) and Microsoft Deployment Toolkit (MDT) server and was responsible for task sequence configuration and client system deployment.
- Responsible for Windows and RHEL STIG configuration.
- Works with Cyber Security attending meetings for TE software and hardware configuration.
- Attends Sigma Six discussions providing useful feedback as a member of a project team.

- Responsible for Test Equipment (TE) computer systems working as a member of a system administration team.
- Participates in system design, security solutions, system imaging, data recovery, hardware diagnostics, and unique problem solutions in multiple heterogeneous network environments.
- Assists with managing user accounts, network access, generation and maintenance of web page content, infrastructure, database support, and system backups.
- Provides solutions to a variety of technical problems of moderate scope and complexity primarily with internal company contacts.
- Responsible for system documentation.
- DoD Secret Security Clearance.

#### SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR (DOE Q SECURITY CLEARANCE)

# CNS Pantex | Amarillo, TX | December 2015 - March 2019

- Attended weekly Vulnerability Assessment Management meetings and help responsibility for technical patching on Pantex systems. Security patching included Microsoft and 3<sup>rd</sup> party applications.
- Calculated Site Performance Review (SPR) monthly metrics, and reviewed system compliance on the Pantex network. Average monthly system compliance on the Pantex network was 99% compliant.
- Reviewed and approved non-standard security exceptions for individual users and systems.
- Developed security protocols and procedures using various tools including PowerShell scripts, SCCM, Group Policy, Active Directory, Tenable, Splunk, Citrix, and more.
- Created and configured standalone system media for government issued laptops which included Cisco AnyConnect VPN software.
- Acted as a direct contact for PeopleSoft, Java, Acrobat, Reader, Flash Player, and deployments.
- Acted as a direct contact for any VPN related issues.
- DoE Q Top Secret Security Clearance

#### HIGH-PERFORMANCE COMPUTING RESEARCHER

#### Los Alamos National Laboratory | Los Alamos, NM | May 2015 - August 2015

- Researched object storage software called Ceph.
- Contributed work to a team of 3 computer science interns.
- Conducted read and write tests on a computer cluster of 11 nodes. Increased performance of default configuration of Ceph object storage software by 11%.
- Built a Linux computer cluster of 11 nodes and configured DNS, DHCP, NTP, NFS, HTTP, Authentication and Authorization, Users and Groups, LDAP, and Kerberos.

#### Education

### BACHELOR OF ARTS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

# New Mexico State University | Las Cruces, NM | January 2014 - December 2015

Followed my passion for computers and programming and excelled in Java and C programming courses. Completed network security and architecture courses. Researched high performance computer software and completed my senior project on Ceph Object Storage software. Also minored in Software Development and Algorithms Theory. Graduated with a 3.5 GPA.

# BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN BIOLOGY

## New Mexico State University | Las Cruces, NM | August 2007 - May 2013

Completed studies in Biology and continued on to work in an environmental laboratory. Minored in Biochemistry. Graduated with a 3.5 GPA.